A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Office and Home Files FA1353
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Projects and Properties, 1923-2009; 3; 76.78 Cubic Feet 177 containers
  - Wyoming, 1937-2009; 3_13
    - LSR Preserve/JY Ranch, 1937-2008; 3_13_2
      - JY Ranch - Moyer, Peter F. - Moose - Wilson Road, 2005-2006 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - JY Ranch - JY Ranch Plan - Pre-Planning, 1994-2001 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - JY Ranch - JY Ranch Plan - General, 1990-2002 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - JY Ranch - Ranch Summer Visits, 1993-2003 (Box 24, Folder 3-13)
      - JY Ranch - Staff - General, 1976-2002 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - JY Ranch - Staff - Cheryl Lasek (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - JY Ranch - Staff - Laughlins (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - JY Ranch - General, 1998-2004 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - JY Ranch - "A Plan for the Future" Brochure, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - JY Ranch - Ralph Applebaum Associates, Inc., 2003 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - JY Ranch - Assessment Reports and Biological Assessment, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - JY Ranch - Carney Architects, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - JY Ranch - Sibbett Group, 2003-2005 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
      - JY Ranch - Wetlands Delineation - Pioneer Environmental Services, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - LSR Preserve - JY Budgets and Reports, 2000-2007 (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - LSR Preserve - Interpretation - LSR Speeches and Quotes - Research, 1954-2006 (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - LSR Preserve - LSR Speeches and Quotes - Research, 1993-2006 (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - LSR Preserve - Maintenance Fund, 2005-2008 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - LSR Preserve - Oral History, 2007 (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - LSR Preserve - Property Maintenance Plan, 2006-2007 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - LSR Preserve - Publicity, 2004-2006 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - LSR Preserve - Section 106 Issues - National Park Service, 2002-2004 (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - LSR Preserve - Williams, Terry Tempest, 2005-2006 (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - LSR Preserve - Timetable, 2001-2003 (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - LSR Preserve - Trail Construction Contract, 2006 (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - LSR Preserve - Trail Guide, 2007 (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - LSR Preserve - Transfer to National Park Service, 2007 (Box 90, Folder 10)
      - LSR Preserve - Visitor Center - General, 2006-2007 (Box 90, Folder 11)
      - LSR Preserve - Visitor Center - Dedication Ceremony, 2008 June 21 (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - LSR Preserve - Visitor Center - Exhibits, 2006-2008 (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - LSR Preserve - Visitor Center - Interpretation, 2001-2007 (Box 90, Folder 14)
      - LSR Preserve - Working Group List, 2008 (Box 90, Folder 15)
      - Wyoming - LSR Land Purchase for Children, 2001-2004 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - JY Ranch - Album of Letters of Memories of the JY Ranch and Gratitude to LSR from Family and Friends, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 7)
        Album assembled by Bobbie Laughlin.
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Planning, 2001 (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Guest List, 2001 (Box 96, Folder 4)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - LSR Travel, 2001 May 25-May 27 (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - LSR Speech, 2001 May 26 (Box 96, Folder 6)
        LSR Speech presenting the JY Ranch to the American People. Folder contains LSR's original speaking copy with his underlinings and notes, as well as background materials.
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Remarks - Secretary of the Interior Gale A. Norton, 2001 May 26 (Box 96, Folder 7)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Remarks - Vice President Dick Cheney, 2001 May 26 (Box 96, Folder 8)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Booklet, 2001 May 26 (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Press Releases, 2001 May 26 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Press Coverage, 2001 May (Box 95, Folder 2, Box 97, Folder 3)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Informal Photos, 2001 May 26 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - JY Ranch - Presentation Ceremony - Correspondence and Photos with Vice President Cheney, 2001 (Box 97, Folder 5)
      - JY Ranch - Transfer - Letters to LSR and LSR Responses, 2001 (Box 97, Folder 6)
      - JY Ranch - Art Collection - Storage Lease Agreement, 2004-2006 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - JY Ranch - Art Collection - Appraisal - Retreat Cabin, 2003 (Box 98, Folder 2)
      - JY Ranch - Art Collection - Appraisal, 2003 (Box 98, Folder 3)
      - JY Ranch - Art Collection - General, 2002-2005 (Box 98, Folder 4)
      - JY Ranch - Land Transfers, 1983-2001 (Box 98, Folder 5)
      - JY Ranch - History, 1937-2001 (Box 98, Folder 6)
      - JY Ranch - General, 1999-2003 (Box 98, Folder 7)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Property, 1986-2001 (Box 98, Folder 8)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Ranch Inventory - Equipment and Vehicles, 2004-2007 (Box 98, Folder 8A)
      - JY Ranch - Easements, 1970-2001 (Box 98, Folder 9)
      - JY Ranch - Roads and Cabins (Box 98, Folder 10)
      - JY Ranch - Chappell Report - Architectural History, 2002-2003 (Box 98, Folder 11)
      - JY Ranch - Magazine Article, 2003 (Box 98, Folder 12)
      - National Park Service - Management Policies, 2001 (Box 98, Folder 13)
      - National Park Service - General, 1995-2007 (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - National Park Service - Partnerships, 2002-2003 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - LSR Preserve - Trail System, 2005 (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - LSR Preserve - Exhibits, 2004 (Box 99, Folder 4)
      - LSR Preserve - Visitor Center - Exhibits, 2004 (Box 99, Folder 5)
      - LSR Preserve - Historic Preservation Issues, 2001 (Box 101, Folder 12)
      - "A Contribution to the Heritage of Every American" - The Conservation Activities of John D. Rockefeller Jr, 1957 (Box 102, Folder 2)
      - JY Ranch - Relocation of Cabins to Granite Ranch - Photos, 2006 (Box 102, Folder 3)
      - Common Good (Philip K. Howard), 2007 (Box 112, Folder 5)
      - LSR Estate - JY Ranch and Granite Ranch - Proposed Purchases, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - Grand Teton National Park - General, 2000-2008 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Grand Teton National Park - In holdings Study, 2005 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Grand Teton National Park - Transportation Study, 2002 (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - Grand Teton National Park - Visitor Center, 2001-2006 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - LSR Preserve - Photographs, 2005 (Box 116, Folder 5)
      - LSR Preserve - Booklet of LSR Preserve, Trails, Drawings of Visitor Center, 2006 (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - LSR - Speeches, 1941-1999 (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - LSR - Memorial Service - Jackson, Wyoming, 2004 (Box 116, Folder 7)
      - LSR Estate - JY Ranch - Equipment List, 2004 (Box 116, Folder 10)
      - LSR Estate - JY Ranch - Tangible Donations, 2004-2005 (Box 116, Folder 11)
      - LSR Estate - Real Estate - JY Ranch Property Appraisal (Box 116, Folder 12)
      - LSR Estate - Real Estate - JY Ranch Buildings Appraisal, 2004 (Box 116, Folder 13)
      - JY Ranch - Old Photos (Box 116, Folder 14)
      - LSR Estate - Children's Purchase of Estate Tangibles, 2006 (Box 111, Folder 8)
      - LSR Fund - Elliott Galleries - Broom Sweep, 2006-2007 (Box 111, Folder 9)
      - LSR Estate - Legal Files, 1989-1998 (Box 111, Folder 11)
      - LSR Fund - Samueli Institute - General, 2001-2006 (Box 116, Folder 15, Box 117, Folder 1)
      - LSR - Princeton University - Gifts, 2004 May 26 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      - Clayton W. Frye (CWF) - JY Planning - Assorted (Box 123, Folder 3)
      - Buffalo Bill Historical Society, 2001-2004 (Box 123, Folder 4)
      - Clayton W. Frye (CWF) - Appeal to the Great Spirit, 2001-2004 (Box 123, Folder 5)
      - LSR - Letters to Gale A. Norton, Secretary of Interior, 2001 (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - LSR - Memorandum of Understanding for the JY Ranch, 2001 February 1 (Box 123, Folder 7)
      - LSR - Letter to President George W. Bush, 2001 March 1 (Box 123, Folder 8)
        President's support of conservation in budget speech to Congress.
      - LSR - Meeting with Secretary Gale Norton, 2001 April 10 (Box 123, Folder 9)
      - LSR - Laura Chasin - Resolution to LSR on his 80th Birthday, 1990 May 26 (Box 123, Folder 10)
      - Clayton W. Frye (CWF) - Historic Hudson Valley Resolution of Thanks to CWF, 2005 February 24 (Box 123, Folder 11)
      - JY Ranch Plan - Rockefeller Family Correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      - JY Ranch Plan - Gift to LSR Children - Purchase of Granite Ranch, 2004 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - LSR - Letters to Children and Family, 2001-2002 (Box 124, Folder 1)
      - LSR - Letter to Bobbie and Tom Laughlin, 2001 March 1 (Box 124, Folder 2)
        Employment arrangement during JY Ranch transition.
      - LSR Family - Letters to LSR, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 3)
      - JY - Family Letters, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 4)
      - JY - Follow Up, 1999-2000 (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - JY - Follow Up, 2000-2001 (Box 124, Folder 6)
      - JY - Follow Up, 2001-2002 (Box 125, Folder 1)
      - JY - Follow Up, 2003-2004 (Box 125, Folder 2)
      - LSR - Wyoming Property, 1978-1990 (Box 130, Folder 3)
      - LSR Preserve Center - Leed Platinum Submission and Review Documentation Report, 2007 (Box 138, Folder 11)
      - JY Ranch Guestbook, 1973-2003 (Box 160, Folder 2)
      - LSR - JY Ranch - General Correspondence, 2003 (Box 164, Folder 2)
      - JY Ranch - 1986-1987 - Appraisal - Young's Creek Tract (Box 172, Folder 2-3)
      - JY Ranch - Newspaper and Newsletter Articles, 1985-1986 (Box 172, Folder 4)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Mineral Rights - Powder River Basin, 1986 (Box 172, Folder 5)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Dartmouth College Gift, 1982 (Box 172, Folder 6)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Report on Conservation Easement, 1986-1988 (Box 173, Folder 1)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Young's Creek Tract for MSKCC, 1988 (Box 173, Folder 2)
      - LSR Preserve - General, 2001-2008 (Box 173, Folder 3)
      - LSR Preserve - Albright, Joseph - Correspondence and Article, 2006 (Box 173, Folder 4)
      - LSR Preserve - Appraisal, 2007 (Box 173, Folder 5)
      - LSR Preserve - JHPI Support in Jackson Hole Area, 2001 (Box 173, Folder 6)
      - LSR Preserve - Lujan, Manuel, Jr. - LSR Letter, 1990 March 5 (Box 173, Folder 7)
      - LSR Preserve - Legal Permits, 2001 (Box 173, Folder 8)
      - LSR Preserve - LSR Pledge Letters, 2001 (Box 173, Folder 9)
      - LSR Preserve - JY Cabins, 2001-2005 (Box 173, Folder 10)
      - LSR Preserve - Signed Memorandum of Understanding, 2001 (Box 173, Folder 11)
      - LSR Preserve - Conveyance to National Park Service (Box 173, Folder 12)
      - LSR Preserve - Easement Issue, 2001-2007 (Box 173, Folder 13)
      - LSR Preserve - Exhibit Fabrication Contract, 2005-2006 (Box 173, Folder 14)
      - LSR Preserve - HABS Study, 2003-2004 (Box 173, Folder 15)
      - LSR Preserve - General, 2001-2004 (Box 174, Folder 1)
      - LSR Preserve - Consultants - Carney Architects, 2002-2004 (Box 174, Folder 2)
      - LSR Preserve - Consultants - Coffee, Kevin, 2003 (Box 174, Folder 3)
      - LSR Preserve - Consultants - Design Workshop, 2003 (Box 174, Folder 4)
      - LSR Preserve - Consultants - James, Clay, 2002-2004 (Box 174, Folder 5)
      - LSR Preserve - Consultants - LeBoeuf, Lamb, Greene and MacRae, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 6)
      - LSR Preserve - Consultants - Sibbett Group - Contract, 2003 (Box 174, Folder 7)
      - LSR Preserve - Correspondence - LSR Children, 2000-2003 (Box 174, Folder 8-11)
        Correspondence with Larry, Lucy, Laura, and Marion.
      - LSR Preserve - Correspondence - Other Rockefeller Family Members, 2001-2002 (Box 174, Folder 12)
      - LSR Estate - Selections - Rockefeller, Larry, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 13)
      - LSR Estate - Selections - Chasin, Laura, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 14)
      - LSR Estate - Selections - Waletzky, Lucy, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 15)
      - LSR Estate - Selections - Weber, Marion, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 16)
      - LSR Estate - Selections - Rockefeller, David, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 17)
      - LSR Estate - Selections - Joint JY Family Selections, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 18)
      - LSR Estate - Appraisals - Miscellaneous, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 19)
        Golf cart, western barn
      - LSR Estate - Miscellaneous Family Requests, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 20)
      - LSR Estate - Miscellaneous - Jim Sligar, Tracy Bentley, 2005 (Box 174, Folder 21)
      - Jackson Hole - General, 1982-1995 (Box 175, Folder 1)
      - JY Ranch - LSR Ranch Inheritance, 1967-1968 (Box 175, Folder 2)
      - JY Ranch - Jackson Lake Dam, 1980-1984 (Box 175, Folder 3)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Gifts to Princeton, 1982 (Box 175, Folder 4)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Gift to MSKCC, 1982 (Box 175, Folder 5)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal - Gift to Vermont Law School, 1983 (Box 175, Folder 6)
      - JY Ranch - Land Transfer Gifts, 1980-1983 (Box 175, Folder 7)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal, 1980 (Box 175, Folder 8)
      - JY Ranch - Appraisal, 1986 (Box 175, Folder 9)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - Drilling, 1986-1988; 1988 (Box 175, Folder 10-12)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - Materials for 1990 Congressional Hearing (Box 175, Folder 13)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - Preparation Plan, Powder River Regional Team, 1985 (Box 176, Folder 1)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - Signed Agreement - LSR and Department of the Interior, 1985 (Box 176, Folder 2)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - One-Acre Conservation, 1993 (Box 176, Folder 3)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - Environmental Assessment, 1986-1989 (Box 176, Folder 4)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - Appraisal, 1985 (Box 176, Folder 5)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange, 1985-1988 (Box 176, Folder 6-9)
      - JY Ranch - Easement Exchange - Litigation, 1989-1992 (Box 177, Folder 1-4)
      - LSR - JY Ranch - Slides, 1978 September (Box 342, Folder 5)